Preksha Anand

Human Resource Professional

CONTACT

■ preksha4work@gmail.com
□ 9999791406, 9958081406

ABOUT ME

https://www.linkedin.com/in/preksha-anand-a338a4b0/

Seasoned with more than 6 years of experience in various Human Resource protocols, which include HR Generalist with a successful track record. Demonstrated acumen in planning, directing and coordinating human resource management activities of the organization to maximize the strategic use of human resources. Proficient in all HRrelated tasks. As an experienced HR professional, my aim would be, to utilize my HR experience in the best possible way.

Resume created on DoYouBuzz

EXPERIENCE

Human Resource Manager

Plunes Technologies Pvt. Ltd. - Since July 2019 - Full-time - Gurgaon



- ▶ Initiating HR processes as per the organization's capabilities and standard practices.
- Setting up HR Systems & Processes to Providing HR Support to Business and Organizational Development.
- ► Expertise in building key People Programmes.
- ▶ Developing and Conducting Competency-Based Talent Assessment Methodologies.
- ▶ Talent Management.
- ▶ Formulating and implementing strategies for effective employee engagement.
- ► Compliance Management.

Manager-Talent Management & Communication



Carre4re Consulting - Since August 2017 - Full-time - Gurgaon - India

Designed & executed various HR projects for clients like Hero MotoCorp. Futl

- ▶ Designed & executed various HR projects for clients like Hero MotoCorp, Future Generali India Insurance Company Ltd., Becton Dickinson India, Great Place to Work India, Jubilant Life Sciences, to name a few.
- ▶ Creating HR communication strategies for client needs keeping the HR intent at the base.
- ► Conceptualizing creative framework for effective branding & communication of products in HR domain/HR interventions.
- Developing a framework & strategy for change management interventions/HR communication initiatives.
- ▶ Acting as a crucial link between the frame working of the strategy and its transfer onto a creative canvas. End to end management of HR communication projects for various clients.
- ▶ Contributing to the creative space as a Graphic Designer & Script Writer (more of getting the work done) by formulating out of the box ideas for effective communications of HR strategy.
- ▶ Working with the creative and content team to convert ideas into designs and delivery of project as per schedule.
- ▶ Working on various HR projects in the space of Talent Management, Organisational Development, Performance Management, Learning & Development, HR Communications, Change Management and so forth.
- ▶ I was awarded 'STAR PERFORMER' for one of my projects.

Human Resource Manager



AntiAlias Ventures Pvt. Ltd. - December 2016 to July 2017 - Fulltime - New Delhi - India

- Responsible for building the whole HR department from scratch.
- ▶ Understanding the business needs and work closely with external or internal partners on leadership development/ recruitment needs in line with business growth.
- ▶ Leading the HR function and be a key member of the leadership team and working closely with key stakeholders to create and delivering the HR strategy for the business and ensure that the business objectives are met.
- Responsible for the entire documentation process of HR Department.
- ▶ Handling the Employee reference check process for new joiners.
- Preparing monthly payroll employees, calculating overtime, creating codes for new employees, updating personal details, salary details and passport details of the employees.
- ► Executing end to end HR framework and policies while setting up processes for recruitment and leadership development needs, performance management etc.
- ▶ Totally responsible for day to day activities like drafting of letters/all the HR related paperwork, scheduling & handling initial round of interviews, along with policy discussion and company briefing.
- ▶ Counseling and supporting employees to have a good employee Relation.
- ▶ Working closely with the support functions to give out awareness and communication of existing or new HR policies from time to time through presentations, focus groups etc.

- ► Timely preparation of Full & Final settlement with no dues clearance formality and relevant document collection.
- ► Inculcating discipline and code of conduct by reinforcing workplace ethics & value systems.
- ▶ Handling entry and exit interview.
- ▶ Leave Records Maintenance, Attendance Keeping, Grievances Handling.
- Working in an automated environment and better the existing policies through reevaluation
- ► Ensuring 100% HRMS Data Accuracy Complete management of in-house/ outsourced associates (including recruitment of vacant positions, attendance, monthly payroll, compliance etc.)
- ▶ Leading & executing various employee engagement activities.
- ▶ Helping Automation of HR process and pushing new tools/system to improve HR systems.

Human Resource Manager (HRBP)



Sparrow Interactive Pvt. Ltd - December 2014 to December 2016 - Full-time - Delhi - India

- ► Leading a team of 3 members. Responsible for all the activities of HR department for the main domain of the company.
- ► Handling end to end Manpower Planning for internal vacancies in alignment with the business requirements of the organization across all locations.
- ► Coordinating with Candidates in terms of arranging interviews.
- ▶ Inducting new joiners to the organization, Schedule and conduct training programs.
- Responsible for the entire documentation process of HR Department.
- ▶ Co-ordinate with accounts department to open salary account for new employees
- ▶ Handling the Employee reference check process for new joiners.
- ▶ Maintain the records of all employees in HRMS.
- ▶ Responsible for assigning Updated Job Responsibilities to the existing and new employees and also to maintain their records.
- ► Totally responsible for day to day activities like drafting of letters, scheduling & handling initial round of interviews, along with policy discussion and company briefing.
- ▶ Counselling and Supporting employees to have a good employee Relation.
- ▶ Responsible to Create, maintain and update all other important information records (Employee advance related, Mobile phones related, Birthday records, Festive bonus related, Original documents & security Deposits related, Employee loan related, Regular notice and circulars etc.)
- Responsible for timely preparation of Full & Final settlement with no dues clearance formality and relevant document collection.
- ▶ Implementation of HR Policies.
- ▶ Handling entry and exit interview.
- ▶ Leave Records Maintaining, Attendance Keeping, Grievances Handling.
- Responsible for various employee engagement activities.

HR Executive - Talent Acquisition

G.Gheewala HR Consultants - September 2013 to September 2014 - Full-time - Mumbai - India

- ► Leading a team of 5 members. Screening, Hiring & shortlisting of the candidates as per the requirement.
- ▶ Coordinating with various departments for the requirement.
- ▶ Calling the candidates & interviewing them.
- ▶ Documentation of the new joiners.
- Arranging the induction program for the new joiners.
- Maintaining the attendance of the employees.
- ▶ Conducting various HR activities to motivate employees.
- ▶ Drafting the advertisements in the newspaper for recruitment.
- Key Successes Include:
- ► Successfully managing 6 overseas projects.
- ▶ Successful completion of all the projects.

▶ Successful track record of placing more than 700 employees

3D Animator

Uno Digital Pvt. Ltd.('Legend 3D' San Diageo) - November 2009 to December 2011 - Full-time - Mumbai - India

I worked as a 3D Animator for Hollywood movies like Transformers: Dark of the Moon, The Smurfs, Ghost Rider: Spirit of Vengence etc.

SKILLS

Human Resource

- ▶ HRBP
- ▶ Talent Acquisition
- ▶ Employee Relations
- ▶ HR Policies & Procedures
- ▶ HR Consulting
- ▶ Onboarding
- ▶ Talent Management
- ▶ Performance Management
- ▶ Employee Engagement
- ▶ Training & Development
- **▶** HRIS
- ▶ Compensation & Benefits
- ▶ Induction Process
- ▶ Joining & Exit Process
- Grivances Handling
- ▶ HR Generalist
- ▶ HR Communication
- ▶ Leadership
- ▶ Change Management

EDUCATION

MBA

Tamilnadu Open University

2010 to 2012

MBA in Human Resource Management.

My Thesis "Entrepreneurship in India" was awarded 1st position during the program.

B.Sc

Vinayaka Missions University

2007 to 2010

B.Sc. in Visual Communication

My Thesis "Color Theory in Multimedia" was awarded 1st position during the program.

Advance Diploma

Maya Academy of Advance Cinematics

2006 to 2007

Advance Diploma in 3D Animation and VFX

INTERESTS

Literature

- ▶ Reading
- Avid Writer.

Currently working on my first book.